

Jenan Jaber Abdulla Ebrahim

Mobile: 00973 32210020

Nationality: Bahraini

Email: jenanjabdulla@gmail.com

D.O.B: 19.10.1989

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I aim towards expanding work knowledge by gaining genuine field experience, enabling the ability to learn by practice in a vibrant working environment, I am a hardworking, friendly and trustworthy person with a wide range of relevant skills including commercial awareness, teamwork and leadership. I am grateful for the knowledge that I am gaining from my degree. I am a quick learner and good listener, which enables to adjust myself to any situation. I consistently work to the highest of my professional standards, and I thrive when working as part of a solid team to deliver projects that yield multiple business benefits.

EDUCATION

University of Huddersfield-United Kingdom:

Bachelor Degree A (Hons) Accountancy Degree September 2008- June 2012

English A Britton College:

International Foundation Year (IFY) 2007-2008

Al-Hoora Secondary School:

General High School Certificate: 2004/2007

SKILLS

Key Skills:

- Extensive Computing Skills.
 - Microsoft Office
 - Microsoft Excel
 - Sage software
 - o Oracle system
 - o NextGen
- Time Management
- Analytical skills

- Languages:
 - Arabic Fluent
 - o English Fluent

WORK EXPERIENCE

1. Banz Group: OCT 2022 - CURRENT

Operation officer

Responsibilities:

- Prepare and coordinate necessary reports such as inventory, shipments and purchase orders.
- Manage warehouse operations, including shipping and receiving, inventory, order processing and cycle count.
- Communicate with management teams to confirm execution of company processes.
- Develop improved business functionality that increases profits.

2. The Benefit Company (SINNAD) SEP2021-AUG 2022

Customer Service (Call center):

Responsibilities:

- Help customers with complaints and questions.
- Generating sales leads that develop into new customers.
- Prepare correspondence and fulfill customer inquiries to ensure customer satisfaction.
- Escalating matters to the respective department for solution.

3. <u>AlSalam Factory for Paper Manufacturing and Paper Product: AUG2017-</u> SEP2020

Procurement Tender Officer:

Responsibilities:

- Analyzed and researched current and new suppliers to understand the availability of products and services, timeframes, and cost.
- Planned and coordinated suppliers-tenders for products and services to ensure that the best deals are available.
- Managed tender processes including documentation, bid evaluations and publication notices.
- Negotiated and renegotiated contacts with suppliers, liaising with other departments that were involved to ensure everyone is happy with the supplier.
- Defined, developed, and implemented the supply chain strategy that aligns with the overall business strategic objective.

4. JBG (Jawad Business Group) MAY 2013-DEC 2015

Accountant:

Responsibilities:

Daily transactions cash flow:

- Handling and supervising the company's daily transactions activities through "Receipt cash book"
 (RCB) in the system, checking out the daily transactions, preparing and approving the transactions
 through the company's system for the final approval of the management.
- Monitoring all daily transactions done in overseas branches of the company and following up on the generated control reports to ensure adherence to the company's Module.
- Validating and signing various requests and transactions according to the approved authority matrix, especially high value transactions and trade finance request.
- Maintain the monthly, semi-annual and annual registers according to the approval policies and procedures.
- Reviewing all relevant documents included within the transaction before submitting for the final approval of the Management.

Budgeting:

- Checking and approving the annual business and expenses for overseas branches of the company in coordination with the concerned department in the Kingdom of Bahrain.
- Reviewing a general list of all planned expenses and revenue.
- Signing/Approving the budget sheet and submitting for final approval.

Reconciliation:

- Reviewing all control reports generated by different systems for monitoring all transactions and
 positions on regular basis to provide our budget on income and outcome flow for the final
 decision/approval of the Management.
- Monitoring and controlling all E-Channels systems for the company to create audit report observation on different products and coordination timely corrective actions implementation.
- Reconciliation of daily transactions received through the system from company's Overseas branches such as Invoices, Petty cash, Customs duty & Freight, Operational report, Banking reconciliation, TT Transfer- Telex transfer, LTR-Local Transfer Letter, Payment vouchers and Sales Report, analysing the transactions and adding/approving in the company's system.

5. BBK (Bank of Bahrain and Kuwait) JUL-SEP 2012

<u>Financial Control Department</u>

Responsibilities:

- Studying, preparing and participating in Audit confirmation Report, preparing audit sheet, detailing the daily transactions of the departments.
- Checking the daily transactions of ATM cards, Trade Finance contingent accounts and ensuring the transactions are processed correctly.
- Reconciliation, FTD accounts with matured status, End of day cash position reconciliation, BCTS-Fees and penalties, Manual activity over WIB account, Manual activity over expense (Debit) account, Deposit changes OD option, Reactivated dormant escheated, Activity on dormant/escheated account, interest Calculation test (Monthly task) and Banks operational loss report.
- Responsible for preparing budget report with close coordination with the department's manager.
- Played role as a member of a team of the department to restructure the department hierarchic, prepared a proposal to the management for further development of the department.

6. BDS (Building Defence System): (Systems providers) MAR-JUN 2012

Administration and Purchasing Department:

Responsibilities:

Administrator/Customer Services Adviser:

Worked as an advisor to the company's customers Inside Kingdom of Bahrain and Overseas introducing the company's products and services and how the system can assist their organization to enhance their position in the market, as well as encouraging the customer to implement such a system which will improve the quality and production of the organization giving them high of my efforts and skills to maintain the product in a way that the customer will agree to my ideas and professionals I provided to them.

Operation/Purchasing Department:

- Reviewing all service providers contracts from a business perspective accompanied by meeting all negotiations with their representatives on all the organization's requirements.
- Responsible for preparing the systems and processes for launching new system products with close coordination with the Information Technology department for configuring the related applications of the customers.
- Conducting and monitoring all finance services to ensure that they are applying the approved policies and procedures.

PLACEMENT OBJECTIVE

• I would like to utilize my accountancy skills by putting them into practice, as this would give me experience and encourage me to work and develop my skills in a dynamic organization.